Guide to the Lee Clark Johns papers, 1960-2016 RL.11597
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Lee Clark Johns papers
1960-2016
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Johns, Lee Clark
RL.11597
13.5 Linear Feet
The collection consists of materials documenting the professional and community activities of the corporate communications specialist Lee Clark Johns from Tulsa, OK. Materials include Materials include presentations, speeches, business contracts, book drafts and copies, articles, and materials related to professional technical writing associations. There is a scrapbook documenting the Battle for HB 1017, an educational reform bill for the state of Oklahoma. Johns' family history and alumni activities on behalf of Duke University are also included.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged into three series: Professional files, Community activities, and Personal files.
Collection Overview
The collection consists of materials documenting the life of Lee Clark Johns, a corporate communications specialst from Tulsa, Oklahoma. Materials include presentations, speeches, business contracts, book drafts and copies, articles, and materials related to professional technical writing associations. There is a scrapbook documenting the Battle for HB 1017, an educational reform bill for the state of Oklahoma. Johns' family history and alumni activities on behalf of Duke University are also included.
Biographical / Historical
Lee Clark Johns is a corporate communications professional specializing in business and technical writing. She founded and ran her company, Strategic Communications, for over 30 years. A native of Tulsa, OK, Johns graduated from Duke University with a degree in English. After an early teaching career, she began a career in corporate communications consulting. Her seminars focused on professional writing and presentation skills. Her clients included many national corporations. Johns is also known as the author of the award-winning book "The Writing Coach" (2004). Her article, "The Filing Cabinet Has a Sex Life: Insights of a Professional Writing Consultant" has been widely reprinted. Johns has also served her local community, helping to establish The John Hope Franklin Center for Reconciliation, which addresses race relations in Tulsa. She was also a founding member of Concerned Oklahomans for Reform of Education, a group that helped pass a state education reform bill.
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Provenance
The Lee Clark Johns papers were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a gift in 2017.
Business writing -- Handbooks, manuals, etc.; Business writing -- Study and teaching; Education policy reform -- Oklahoma; Tulsa (Okla.) -- Commerce; Tulsa (Okla.) -- Race relations; Sallie Bingham Center for Women's History and Culture
- Professional Files, 1979-2016
  Scope and Contents
  Publications and customized notebooks, conference presentations and speeches; samples of customized seminar exercies, calendars, ledgers, and financial records.
  - Professional Writing Consultants ledgers, 1982-2000; 13 folders (Box 1)
  - Strategic Communications ledgers, 2001-2008; 2 folders (Box 1)
  - Wall calendar, 1989 (Box 1)
  - ClearMark, 2016; 3 folders (Box 2)
  - Importance of writing training newspaper clippings, undated (Box 2)
  - Strategic Communications marketing and publicity, undated (Box 2)
  - Publications, 1989-2004 (Box 2)
  - Association of Women in Communications survey, 2002-2004; 3 folders (Box 2)
  - Date books, 1982-2000; 15 folders (Box 2)
  - Date books, 2001-2015; 15 folders (Box 3)
  - Professional writing seminar for college-bound students, 1985-1991; 3 folders (Box 4)
  - Writing effective reports and proposals, city of Tulsa, 1992 (Box 4)
  - Technical writing seminar, 1996 (Box 4)
  - Professional writing seminar, 1996 (Box 4)
  - Effective written communications for auditors, Amoco, 1998 (Box 4)
  - The Writing Coach proofs and publication, 2004; 4 folders (Box 4)
  - Writing Excellence publication, 2006 (Box 4)
  - Getting started in consulting presentation, 2006 (Box 4)
  - Association of Professional Communications Consultants, 1997-2015; 6 folders (Box 4)
  - Association of Professional Writing Consultants awards, 1983-2000; 2 folders (Box 4)
  - Compendium Writing Consultants, 1981 (Box 4)
  - Ethics - ABC presentation, 1990 (Box 4)
  - Montreal presentation, 1993 (Box 4)
  - Conference presentations, 1993-1994 (Box 4)
  - CPL symposium, 2006-2007 (Box 4)
  - Consulting presentation, 2005 (Box 4)
  - Bridging the Gap, 1986 (Box 4)
  - Oil industry consulting, 1989 (Box 4)
  - Writing curriculum, 1994 (Box 4)
  - Plain Language, 2004-2009; 8 folders (Box 4)
  - Writing Excellence book materials, 2002-2003; 10 folders (Box 5)
  - Writing Excellence book, 2005 (Box 5)
  - Coaching adult learners, 2004; 2 folders (Box 5)
  - Strategic Communications website, 2006 (Box 5)
  - More practice, 1981-2002 (Box 5)
  - Writing for the web presentation, 2003 (Box 5)
  - Grammar and punctuation, 1994-2004; 2 folders (Box 5)
  - Writing effective sales letters - transparencies, 2004 (Box 5)
  - Plain language presentation, 2008 (Box 5)
  - ATSD presentation, 2000 (Box 5)
  - Evolution in workplace writing, 2000 (Box 5)
  - American Society of Women Accountants presentation, 1991 (Box 5)
  - 5 favorite fallacies handout, 1992 (Box 5)
  - Petro Report management seminar, 1992 (Box 5)
  - Classics speech, 1989-1991; 2 folders (Box 5)
  - Good writing examples, 1976-2008; 2 folders (Box 5)
  - Diction, 1976-2008; 2 folders (Box 5)
  - Effective presentation skills, 2005 (Box 5)
  - Writing effective email, 2008-2016 (Box 5)
  - Powerful presentations, 2007 (Box 5)
  - Effective presentations, 2005; 2 folders (Box 5)
  - Reader-friendly writing, 2004-2007 (Box 5)
  - Fighting red pen syndrome, 2003 (Box 5)
  - Amoco and Professional Writing Consultants, 1982-2013; 5 folders (Box 6)
  - First Interstate Bank contract, 1988 (Box 6)
  - First National Bank and Trust contract, 1981-1985 (Box 6)
  - Bank of Oklahoma contract, 1983-1986 (Box 6)
  - Benham, Blair, Holloway and Spragins contract, 1978-1989 (Box 6)
  - City of Tulsa Public Works, 1994-2005; 7 folders (Box 6)
  - National Society of Professional Engineers programs, 2004; 3 folders (Box 6)
  - Occidental Petroleum presentations, 1989-1999; 2 folders (Box 6)
  - Tulsa World consulting, 1999-2000; 3 folders (Box 6)
  - Junior League of Tulsa presentation, 1990 (Box 6)
  - What's New in Business Writing speech, 1987-1988 (Box 6)
  - The Sex Life of a Filing Cabinet speech and essay, 1986-1989; 2 folders (Box 6)
  - C of C executive roundtable, 1993 (Box 6)
  - Professional development program notes, 2000 (Box 6)
  - Association of Fundraising Professionals, 2002 (Box 6)
  - Education speeches, 1988-1989 (Box 6)
  - Client permissions for book, 1979-2003 (Box 6)
  - Articles, 2001 (Box 6)
  - PR/Publications, 1996-1997 (Box 6)
  - Association for Women in Communications Lifetime Achievement Award, 2013 (Box 10)
  - White House Fellows application, 1994-1995 (Box 10)
- Community Activities, 1973-2016
  Contains Duke correspondence, Oklahoma education reform papers, materials from the Tulsa launch of the John Hope Franklin Center for Reconciliation, records from the East Michigan Environmental Action Council and a church-sponsored project in Honduras (Perspire)
  - Activities, 1973-2016
    - Leadership Tulsa, 2005-2006 (Box 2)
    - Concerned Oklahomans for Reform in Education, 2015 (Box 2)
    - Cathy Newsome campaign, 2004 (Box 2)
    - Battle for HB 1017 (education reform) scrapbook, 1989-1990 (Box 7)
    - Tulsa Race Riots/Smithsonian document transfer, 2016 (Box 8)
    - John Hope Franklin Center for Reconciliation (Tulsa), 2010-2016; 9 folders (Box 8)
    - Eastern Michigan Environmental Action Council, 1973-1975 (Box 8)
    - Perspire Project (Honduras) diary, scrapbook, photos, 1999; 5 folders (Box 9)
    - Perspire Project (Honduras) documentation, 1999; 3 folders (Box 11)
    - Presbyterian churches - Education, 1994 (Box 11)
    - Overture on public education, 1995 (Box 11)
    - Oklahoma Conference of Churches, 1996 (Box 11)
    - Renaming the partnership: The mainline church in support of public education, 1995 (Box 11)
    - Presbyterian Task Force on Education, 1992-1994 (Box 11)
    - Southminster Presbyterian Church planning retreat, 1997 (Box 11)
    - Southminster Presbyterian Church, 1999-2002; 2 folders (Box 11)
  - Duke University Alumni Activities, 1985-2014
    - Duke Alumni Club, 1985-1987 (Box 8)
    - Duke Alumni Association, 1987-1991 (Box 8)
    - Duke reunions, 1988-1989 (Box 8)
    - Duke Alumni Association presidency, 1991-1992 (Box 8)
    - Duke Alumni Program Think Tank, 1990 (Box 8)
    - Alumni survey, 1990 (Box 8)
    - Duke Alumni Board, 1990-1993 (Box 8)
    - Duke Communications Committee, 1990-1995 (Box 8)
    - Duke Faculty/alumni Committee, 1992 (Box 8)
    - Duke Alumni Scholarship, 1992-2013 (Box 8)
    - Duke Reunions, 2005-2014; 3 folders (Box 8)
    - Duke Alumni Association correspondence, 1990-2014 (Box 8)
    - Duke Board of Trustees meeting, 1992 (Box 8)
    - Duke Women's Studies Council, 1992-1998; 2 folders (Box 8)
    - Women and Power conference, 2001 (Box 8)
    - Articles on Duke, 1991 (Box 8)
    - Duke Development, 1994-2000 (Box 8)
    - John Hope Franklin Center (Duke University), 2007-2009 (Box 8)
    - Duke University class directories, 1992-1995; 2 folders (Box 9)
- Personal Files, 1960-2015
  High school, college, and young adult activities
  - Correspondence and personal files
    - Personal records, 1963-1973 (Box 10)
    - Correspondence, 1963-1964; 8 folders (Box 9)
    - Correspondence from Phil, 1963-1964 (Box 9)
    - Duke University graduation, 1964 (Box 8)
    - University of Kansas Educational Placement Bureau, 1965 (Box 4)
    - University of Kansas transcript and teaching career documentation, 1966-1976 (Box 4)
    - Pandora the Sex Symbol play by Randall Kent Lovett, 1966 (Box 4)
    - Divorce settlement, 1976-1977 (Box 10)
    - Family history, 1976-1988 (Box 9)
    - Laurie Johns' school album, 1976-1982 (Box 9)
    - Lauren Johns correspondence, 1989-1994; 3 folders (Box 9)
    - Address book, varsity letter, card from Laurie, undated (Box 9)
    - American Association for Training and Development certificate, 1981 (Box 4)
    - Correspondence, 1990-2012 (Box 10)
    - Passing of Eleanor Imler, Johns' mother, 1995; 2 folders (Box 9)
    - Family Christmas cards sent, 1995-2015 (Box 10)
    - Christmas cards received, undated (Box 9)
    - Newspaper articles on the Johns family, 1998 (Box 9)
    - Postcards, undated (Box 9)
    - Letter from mother, undated (Box 9)
  - Photographs
    - Headshots, 1960 (Box 8)
    - Wedding photos, undated (Box 8)
    - Family photos, 1960-1970 (Box 8)
    - Family photos, 1970-1980; 8 folders (Box 8)